cerner.com 2017-06-04

# Privacy | Cerner

Cerner has self-certified to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework.

This site uses cookies to ensure you get the best experience on our website. By continuing to use this site, you consent to the use of cookies. More information.

## Overview

Cerner Corporation, its subsidiaries and its affiliates ("Cerner") is committed to protecting the privacy and security of its users. Cerner’s goal is to provide you with a personalized Internet experience that delivers the information, resources and services that are most relevant and helpful to you. In order to achieve this goal, Cerner sometimes collects information during your visits to understand what differentiates you from other users of Cerner.com. Cerner operates under the following set of strict privacy principles:

  * The only information Cerner obtains about individual users to its Web site is that supplied voluntarily by users.
  * In cases when Cerner may need personal information to provide users with customized content or to inform them about new features or services, users are explicitly asked for that information.
  * Personally identifiable information provided by users (name, e-mail or home address, etc.) will not be disclosed to anyone unless users indicate that Cerner may do so, or unless required by law, in conjunction with a government inquiry, or in litigation or dispute resolution.
  * Only statistical information about Cerner.com users as a group (usage habits, demographics) may be shared with any affiliate, subsidiary, sponsor, advertiser or partner of Cerner, unless an appropriate confidentiality agreement is in place. Cerner employs strict security measures to safeguard online transactions. All personal information is stored in a secured database.

The following discloses Cerner’s information gathering and dissemination practices for Cerner.com. Additional terms and conditions, if any, regarding the collection and use of your information may also be provided to you before you sign up for a particular service. Here you will learn what personally identifiable information of yours is collected, how and when Cerner might use your information, how Cerner protects your information, who has access to your information, and how you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

Your privacy is important to us. By participating in the Council of Better Business Bureau's BBBOnLine® Privacy Program we have made a commitment to meet the program’s strict requirements regarding how we treat your information and have it verified by BBBOnLine. Further information about this program is available at [http://www.bbbonline.org](http://www.bbbonline.org/).

### What Information is Collected

Cerner collects certain information from its users in three ways: (a) from Cerner Web server logs, (b) with cookies and (c) directly from the user.

(a) IP Addresses (Server Log Information)

An IP address is a number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. All computer identification on the Internet is conducted with IP addresses, which allow computers and servers to recognize and communicate with each other. Cerner collects IP addresses in order to conduct system administration, report aggregate information to affiliates, subsidiaries, sponsors, advertisers or partners, and to conduct site analysis. Cerner will also use IP addresses to identify any users who refuse to comply with Cerner's Terms of Use Agreement, and to identify users who threaten Cerner’s service, site, user, clients or others.

(b) Cookies

Cerner places a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. Cookies are pieces of information that a Web site transfers to an individual's hard disk for record keeping purposes. Cerner.com uses cookies during your online session to deliver content specific to your interests. Cookies allow Cerner to avoid showing you the same ad or other message repeatedly. Cerner Web Site cookies do not contain personal information. They do enable Cerner to relate your use of the site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided to Cerner.com.

(c) Web Analytics

Cerner may use Google Analytics to understand Cerner.com's site usage. Site usage information is used to help design, develop, and support Cerner.com. To the extent Cerner uses Google Analytics Google receives and stores Cerner.com’scontributed site usage information (such as pages accessed), but it does not receive any individually identifiable or sensitive information as a part of this process. If you do not want data collected by Google Analytics, you can use the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) available on Google's website.

(d) Registration (User-Supplied Information)

Cerner.com site registration systems require users to give Cerner contact information such as their name and e-mail address, and demographic information such as organization and/or role. The user's contact information is used to contact the user when necessary. Users may choose (opt-in) to receive future mailings; see the choice/opt-in section below. Cerner uses this data to tailor the user's experience at Cerner.com, showing the user content that reflects their stated preferences. This information may be shared with affiliates, subsidiaries, sponsors, advertisers or partners on an aggregate basis, but personally identifiable information will not be disclosed without the user’s prior consent.

### Services (User-Supplied Information)

If you sign up for a particular service Cerner may collect personally identifiable information such as contact information (e.g., name, address, telephone number and e-mail address), demographic information (e.g., zip code, organization and/or role), billing information (e.g., credit or debit card numbers), or sensitive information (e.g., social security number, healthcare information).

We use the information to verify that only authorized users are accessing the respective application; to build your electronic client record or electronic personal health record so that Cerner may provide you the specific personalized service you have applied for and agreed with; and to contact you when necessary, to communicate helpful tips and advice during your participation to this service.

### External Links

In order to provide users with greater value, Cerner may provide links to various third party Web sites. However, even if a third-party affiliation exists between Cerner and that destination site, Cerner exercises no authority over linked sites, each of which maintains independent privacy and data collection policies and procedures. Cerner assumes no responsibility or liability for these independent methods or actions and is not responsible for the independent policies or procedures of destination sites. Similarly, Cerner cannot take responsibility for the privacy initiatives or the content of such Web sites. These destination links are provided only for your convenience, and as such, you access them at your own risk. However, Cerner wishes to ensure the integrity of the Cerner Web site and its destination links, so any comments pertaining to Cerner.com or any sites accessed through Cerner links are greatly appreciated. See the Contacting this Web Site section below.

### Surveys and Questionnaires

Cerner.com online surveys and questionnaires may ask users for contact and demographic information. The user's contact information is used to contact the user when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-in section below. Demographic and profile data is also collected at Cerner.com. This information may be shared with affiliates, subsidiaries, sponsors, advertisers or partners on an aggregate basis, but it does not indicate the identity of individual users.

### E-Commerce

Some Cerner.com web site features may use applications to collect data to facilitate an e-commerce transaction, such as registering you for a specific conference. Cerner will ask your explicit permission to transfer this data to a third party (e.g., conference coordinator) to facilitate this transaction. Cerner may store this information to verify the transaction for customer service and accounting reasons and may use this information to help personalize your experience on Cerner.com. Cerner may also share this information with other third parties on an aggregate basis, but it does not indicate the identity of individual users. See the External Links section above for additional disclaimers regarding third-party Web sites.

### Contests

Cerner may run contests on Cerner.com in which users are asked for contact and demographic information. The user's contact information is used to contact the user when necessary. Users may choose to receive future mailings; see the choice/opt-in section below. Demographic and profile data is also collected at Cerner.com. This information is shared with affiliates, subsidiaries, sponsors, advertisers or partners on an aggregate basis, but it does not indicate the identity of individual users.

### Third Party Ad Services

Cerner may utilize certain third-party advertising services to display advertising for its advertisers. These third-party services may place a cookie on your computer for the purposes of ad tracking and presentation. Cerner does not share personally identifiable user information with its advertising services.

### Security

Cerner.com has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under Cerner’s control. Cerner employs strict security measures to safeguard online transactions. All personal information is stored in a secured database.

### Children’s Privacy Protection

The Web Site covered by this privacy policy is not designed for or targeted at children. Cerner will not knowingly collect and maintain personally identifiable information from children 13 years of age or younger.

### Choice/Opt-In; Review/Correct/Update; Contacting the Web Site

Cerner.com gives users the opportunity to opt-in to receive communications from Cerner at the point where Cerner requests information about the user. This site also gives users the options listed below for removing their information from Cerner’s database in order to stop receiving communications or Cerner’s service; for reviewing, changing and modifying information previously provided (subject to reasonable frequency limitations, which Cerner has established as three or fewer requests per year); or should you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this Web site, or your interaction with this Web site:

  * You can send e-mail to: [webmaster@cerner.com](mailto:webmaster@cerner.com)
  * You can call the following telephone number: (816) 201-1122
  * You can send mail to the following postal address: 

> Cerner.com  
>  Cerner Corporation  
>  2800 Rockcreek Parkway  
>  North Kansas City, Missouri 64117-2551

As mentioned in the Terms of Use Agreement, ‘Modification of These Terms of Use’ section, Cerner reserves the right to change the terms, conditions, and notices under which the Cerner.com Web Site is offered, including but not limited to any changes associated with the use of the Cerner.com Web Site now or in the future. You are responsible for regularly reviewing these terms and conditions. However, please note that we will give Web users the opportunity to opt-out or prohibit new/unrelated uses of their personal information.

EFFECTIVE DATE: SEPTEMBER 8, 2001

REVISED DATE: APRIL 11, 2012
